<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Smart City Home on SMU Smart City Society</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/</link><description>Recent content in Smart City Home on SMU Smart City Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Code for Cities 2022</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/upcoming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/upcoming/</guid><description>Please keep a lookout for this page, more details are coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Smart City Themes 2022</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/news/smartcitythemes2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/news/smartcitythemes2022/</guid><description>Hi everyone, Smart City Society presents our four Smart City themes for 2022. Here are the 4 themes:
Feb-March: Smart Living
April-June: Smart People
July-September: Smart Mobility
October-December: Smart Economy
Do keep a lookout for talks, byte-sized posts and our annual Hackathon in the upcoming months!</description></item><item><title>We are Smart City Society!</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/news/wearesmartcitysociety/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/news/wearesmartcitysociety/</guid><description>Greetings from Smart City Society! We have recently transited to a student club under the Institute of Innovation and Entrepreneurship (IIE) and renamed ourselves from SMU Anthill Society to SMU Smart City Society. We will still be focusing on Smart Cities and its related technologies that help urbanization problems through various avenues such as talks, workshops and hackathons. Additionally, we are now a student chapter of Association for Public Affairs (APA).</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/about/</guid><description>about</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/page/aboutus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/page/aboutus/</guid><description>We are a student club under the Institute of Innovation and Entrepreneurship (IIE) which aims to value-add student experiences in the field of Smart-City Management and Technology through workshops which incorporate topical discussions on Smart City issues. Our members will also get to participate in workshops and hackathons, and apply technologies such as analytics and IoT to help solve urbanization problems.
Our club began in 2019 as SMU Anthill Society as an Special Interest Group under Ellipsis, the student representative body of the SMU School of Computing &amp;amp; Information Systems (SCIS).</description></item><item><title>Analysis of the Built Environment</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/team_renergii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/team_renergii/</guid><description>As part of the Smart Nation Primer, Team SMU-Renergii worked on an analysis of Circularity in the Built Environment, with a case study on Singapore.
The scope of their analysis looked at the 5 different building blocks of the built environment - Buildings, Transportation, Water, Waste and Energy. Using the circularity framework by the Ellen Macarthur Foundations, the group analyzed the circularity of current strategies adopted by Singapore and identified business opportunities for circularity innovation.</description></item><item><title>Exco</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/exco/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/exco/</guid><description>exco</description></item><item><title>Geospatial Analysis of Foreign Workers Dormitories in Singapore</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/team_niftie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/team_niftie/</guid><description>As part of the Smart Nation Primer, Team Niftie @ SMU did a geospatial visualization of locations of foreign workers dormitories in Singapore. Using the folium library in python, the students plotted a heatmap to show the distribution of the location of the dormitories.</description></item><item><title>Real time Geospatial Analysis of harmful gas emissions</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/team_traffic_physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/team_traffic_physics/</guid><description>By using real-time open source dataset of traffic images, Team Traffic Psychics created a Computer Vision model that analyses vehicular density at a particular location. By doing so they were able to calculate corresponding emissions data to monitor total harmful gas emissions of an area. Their analysis is also shown on a simple and intuitive dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Save Water Wally</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/teamwonkies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/teamwonkies/</guid><description>In their proposed solution for the Code for Cities hackathon orgainzed by SMU Anthill and Surbana Jurong, Team Wonkies seeks to tackle the problem of water wastage in Singapore via a complementary 2-pronged approach, a mobile phone application, SaveWaterWally, and an external smart detector. Their solution seeks to help users cultivate water saving habit and reduce water wastage in Singapore by tracking and analyzing water usage data.</description></item><item><title>Vertical Farming to solve Food Security problems in Singapore</title><link>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/team_tonton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>smusmartcitysociety.vercel.app/projects/team_tonton/</guid><description>For the Code for Cities hackathon organized by SMU Anthill and Surbana Jurong, Team TonTon chose to tackle the area of Food Security in Singapore. Their solution was to conduct vertical farming at HDB rooftops and pedestrian bridges, so that Singapore would reduce food reliance from other countries. As part of their analysis, they&amp;rsquo;ve also used machine learning models like clustering to cluster farms together based on their natural conditions and Artificial Neutral Networks to predict the future natural conditions of farms.</description></item></channel></rss>